Guide to the photograph album Royal Air Force in Iraq and Sharjah during WWII - Volume I AD.MC.013.v1
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Royal Air Force in Iraq and Sharjah during WWII - vol. 1
1941–1942
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943
AD.MC.013.v1
48 Leaves - 108 gelatin silver prints, 3 poems printed on photographic paper
One oblong album (22 × 16 cm) with 106 photographs (2 coloured) and one oblong album (33 × 24 cm) with 161 photographs, most of them with handwritten captions in English. The photographs vary in sizes, measuring from 4.5 × 6 cm to 25 × 19 cm. The smaller album: string tied tooled black cloth boards, with an ownership inscription in white ink faintly visible at the front bottom. The larger album: string tied beige cloth boards.
This is the first of two photograph albums of Royal Air Force Leading Aircraftman C. J. Sainty, who served in Iraq and the Middle East during World War II. The first 32 photographs are taken during Sainty's period in India and show Bombay and the military camp at Colaba. During the Anglo-Iraq war of 1941, Sainty is transferred to the RAF base at Habbaniya and the photographs show Baghdad and the aircraft base and its residents. A special section entitled "The Fortunes of War. May 1941. R.A.F. v Rebels" is devoted to the Battle of Habbaniya and shows British and Iraqi tanks, guns and fallen aircraft, including a German Messerschmidt Bf 110. A few graphic photos of limbs and cadavers in the desert show the grim human toll of the war. Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks).
Box AD_MC_013_v.1
Arrangement
The collection was processed as it was received.
Biographical / Historical
This pair of photograph albums contains a collection of photographs taken by Royal Air Force Leading Aircraftman C.J. Sainty, who served in Iraq and the Middle East during World War II. The photographs were taken in India, Iraq and Sharjah in 1941–43, including the Battle of Habbaniya (1941).
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions at akkasah.org. For access to physical album contact Akkasah Center for Photography, akkasah@nyu.edu +971 2628 5531
Scope and Contents
The first 32 photographs in this collection were taken during Sainty's period in India and show Bombay/Mumbai and the military camp at Colaba. During the Anglo-Iraq war of 1941, Sainty was transferred to the RAF base at Habbaniya and the photographs show Baghdad and the aircraft base and its residents. A special section entitled "The Fortunes of War. May 1941. R.A.F. v Rebels" is devoted to the Battle of Habbaniya and shows British and Iraqi tanks, guns and fallen aircraft, including a German Messerschmidt Bf 110. A few graphic photos of limbs and cadavers in the desert show the less glamorous side of the war. The second album shows many pictures of the cities of Baghdad and Basra. The photographs of Ashar, the heart of Basra, show daily life in this ancient city: a boatman, Arabian policemen in long coats, a barber, a craftsman, machine shop workers, a bread maker, a copper beater, long hand crafted river boats and a camel caravan. Photographs of a trip to northern Iraq show daily life in the country and endless vistas of desolate hills. The album concludes with various photographs of camp life at the RAF base in Sharjah.
Custodial History
Akkasah, the Center for Photography at NYU Abu Dhabi, acquired the collection in December 2015.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Album purchased from Antiquariat Inlibris, Rathausstraße 19, 1010 Wien, Austria, in 2015.
Iraq; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; United Arab Emirates; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Mumbai/Bombay, India
- The front cover of RAF in Iraq and Sharjah VI., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_afr01; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Iraq; Sharjah, United Arab Emirates; Mumbai/Bombay, India
- Inside front cover of The front cover of RAF in Iraq and Sharjah VI., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_afr02; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
- Clockwise from top left: views of a cape from a ship, a portrait of a serviceman and street views of Bombay (Mumbai), India., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000001; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Children; Men; Individual Portraits; Boats/Ships; Cars/Trucks; Mumbai/Bombay, India; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Royal Air Force; Transportation; Streets/Roads; Water; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers
- Fruit sellers, a shoe shiner and knife grinder in Bombay (Mumbai)., 1941; nyuad_pa000001_n000002; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Photographic Prints; Men; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Mumbai/Bombay, India; Workers; Individual Portraits; Fez/Tarboush; Street Vendors; Streets/Roads; Food; Hats
- Clockwise from top left: a hackery, the Prince of Wales Museum in Bombay (Mumbai), a soldier reading, and a charpai bed., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000003; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Men; Individual Portraits; Museums; Mumbai/Bombay, India; Cattle/Cows; Animals; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Royal Air Force; Carriages/Coaches; Transportation; Newspapers/Magazines; Uniforms; Streets/Roads; Military/Soldiers; Furnishings
- Portraits of a man sitting in an alley with a dog., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000004; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Men; Dogs; Animals; Unknown Locations; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits
- Clockwise from top left: views of a building before and after rain, general city street views, and a view of Hornby Road (Dadabhai Naoroji Road)., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000005; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Mumbai/Bombay, India; Streets/Roads; Men; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Horses; Animals; Cars/Trucks; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Carriages/Coaches; Transportation; Fez/Tarboush; Buses; Architecture; Hats
- A Portrait of a woman with a man, and a portrait of the same woman., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000006; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  England, UK; Men; Women; Group Portraits; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Smoking; Tobacco pipes
- Page captioned "Some pukka sahibs". Clockwise from top left: Group portraits of servicemen with Inidan Chefs, five men posing by a swimming pool, three group portraits of men wearing pith helmets., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000007; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Group Portraits; Men; Swimming Pools; Uniforms; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; India; Royal Air Force; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Chefs/Cooks; Military/Soldiers
- An empty page of the album., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000008; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Iraq; Mumbai/Bombay, India; Sharjah, United Arab Emirates
- Clockwise from top left: men at a Breach Candy Club in Bombay (Mumbai), a street view from the canteen of the base at Colaba, Mahatma Gandhi Road in Bombay (Mumbai), and the Gateway of India, Bombay (Mumbai)., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000009; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Swimming Pools; Men; Mumbai/Bombay, India; Group Portraits; Streets/Roads; Animals; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Colāba, Mumbai, India; Architecture; Royal Air Force; Carriages/Coaches; Cars/Trucks; Transportation; Street Lamps; Military/Soldiers
- Two portraits of servicemen., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000010; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Uniforms; Men; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Unknown Locations; Smoking; Gelatin Silver Prints; Royal Air Force; Tobacco pipes; Military/Soldiers; Pottery; Military/Soldiers
- Portraits of servicemen stationed in Colaba, Bombay (Mumbai) alongside Indian workers., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000011; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Uniforms; Men; Group Portraits; Individual Portraits; English Writing; Royal Air Force; Colāba, Mumbai, India; Turbans; Regional/National Dress; Military/Soldiers
- The sign for the Royal Air Force base in Habbaniyah, Iraq, indicating the distance to Baghdad and London., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000012; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Arabic Writing; English Writing; Al Habbaniyah (Habbaniya), Al-Anbar Province, Iraq; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Royal Air Force; Signs/Signposts
- Clockwise from top left: Iraqi men and women, a mosque in Baghdad, and three men near a camel., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000013; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Iraq; Men; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Mosques; Baghdad, Iraq; Camels; Group Portraits; English Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Religious Sites; Animals; Regional/National Dress; Turbans
- From left to right: People passing over the Fallujah Bridge, and two images the RAF base Habbaniyah., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000014; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Al Habbaniyah (Habbaniya), Al-Anbar Province, Iraq; Bridges; Rivers; Men; Women; Gardens; Hospitals; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Royal Air Force; Al-Fallujah, Iraq; Group Portraits; Arabic Writing; Military/Soldiers
- Portraits of four servicemen in Iraq., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000015; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Men; Iraq; Individual Portraits; Uniforms; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers
- Clockwise from left to right: A chatty (cooking vessel), a view of Sealand Road, and Air Headquarters Iraq., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000016; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Iraq; Streets/Roads; Royal Air Force; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Cannons; Weapons
- The shoreline around Lake Habbaniya (Habbaniyah) and a portrait of two fishermen., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000017; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Men; Group Portraits; Fishing; Lakes; Al Habbaniyah (Habbaniya), Al-Anbar Province, Iraq; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Uniforms; Royal Air Force; Boats/Ships; Transportation
- A portrait of a man getting out of a pool in Habbaniyah, Iraq., 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000018; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Men; Swimming Pools; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Al Habbaniyah (Habbaniya), Al-Anbar Province, Iraq; English Writing; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Individual Portraits
- Top: men posing in a shed with the caption "Any bets?'. Bottom: a date plantation in Habbaniyah, Iraq., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000019; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Men; Palm Trees; English Writing; Group Portraits; Al Habbaniyah (Habbaniya), Al-Anbar Province, Iraq; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Royal Air Force; Agriculture/Farms; Military/Soldiers
- Cattle being herded., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000020; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Donkeys; Animals; Streets/Roads; Deserts; Unknown Locations; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Transportation
- Habbaniya (Habbaniyah) Cemetery., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000021; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Doors/Entrances; Religious Crosses; Cemeteries; Al Habbaniyah (Habbaniya), Al-Anbar Province, Iraq; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Streets/Roads
- Habbaniya (Habbaniyah) Cemetery., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000022; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Cemeteries; Al Habbaniyah (Habbaniya), Al-Anbar Province, Iraq; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing
- Four portraits of servicemen, one stands in front of a Navy, Army and Air Force Institutes (NAAFI) refreshment facility., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000023; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Men; Smoking; Uniforms; Iraq; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Group Portraits; English Writing; Royal Air Force; Doors/Entrances; Military/Soldiers; Cemeteries; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Military/Soldiers
- Clockwise from top left: the grounds at the back of the Habbaniya camp, a view of Kenley Road, and Air Headquarters Iraq (link ref n000016)., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000024; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Gardens; Al Habbaniyah (Habbaniya), Al-Anbar Province, Iraq; Air Force; Streets/Roads; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Military/Soldiers; Cannons; Weapons
- An album page with English writing: The Fortunes of War. RAF VS Rebels, May 1941; nyuad_pa000001_n000025; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  English Writing; Royal Air Force; Iraq; Mumbai/Bombay, India; Sharjah, United Arab Emirates
- Two photographs of cannons captioned "Iraqi guns"., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000026; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Weapons; Iraq; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Cannons
- Two photographs of armoured vehicles captioned "British-made war tanks and armoured cars, used by rebels"., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000027; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Tanks; Weapons; Iraq; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Royal Air Force; Arabic Writing; Transportation
- Top: A tank; Bottom: a wrecked airplane., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000028; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Tanks; Airplanes; Weapons; Iraq; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Transportation; Royal Air Force
- Two photographs of a wrecked Messerschmitt Bf 110 airplane and servicemen surrounding one., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000029; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Airplanes; English Writing; Men; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; Transportation; Royal Air Force; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers
- Two photographs of the skeletal remains of a body., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000030; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Skeletons; Uniforms; English Writing; Iraq; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Military/Soldiers
- Two photographs of the skeletal remains of a body., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000031; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Skeletons; Uniforms; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; Military/Soldiers
- A hand-tinted photograph of two men and a dog., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000032; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Men; Uniforms; Dogs; Animals; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Deserts; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Iraq; English Writing; Royal Air Force; Deserts; Military/Soldiers; Gelatin Silver Prints
- A hand-tinted photograph of four men wearing matching outfits., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000033; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Men; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Iraq; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; English Writing; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Gelatin Silver Prints
- A poem entitled The Siege of Habbaniyah (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000034; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  English Writing; Al Habbaniyah (Habbaniya), Al-Anbar Province, Iraq; Poetry; Printed Materials; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers
- A poem entitled "The Call of the West" (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000035; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  English Writing; Printed Materials; Poetry; Iraq; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers
- A group portrait of four RAF servicemen - Snapper, Son, Spike, and Johnny in Habbaniyah, Iraq., 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000036; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Men; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Uniforms; Al Habbaniyah (Habbaniya), Al-Anbar Province, Iraq; English Writing; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers
- Left: a shell hole in the roof of the NAAFI canteen. Right: four men in bathing suits., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000037; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Men; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iraq; Royal Air Force; Swimming Pools; Military/Soldiers
- Portraits of men in the Tigris Palace Hotel and overlooking the Tigris River., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000038; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Men; Hotels; Rivers; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iraq; Tigris River; Royal Air Force; Bags/Purses; Water; Military/Soldiers; Furnishings
- Two portraits of the same serviceman., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000039; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Men; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Uniforms; English Writing; Iraq; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers
- Group portraits of three servicemen playing pool/billiards and sitting outdoors., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000040; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Men; Uniforms; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Iraq; Royal Air Force; Sports; Military/Soldiers
- Group portraits of servicemen sitting and riding in a carriage., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000041; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Men; Uniforms; English Writing; Horses; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Animals; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; Royal Air Force; Carriages/Coaches; Transportation; Military/Soldiers
- Left: houses; Right: women carrying water from the Euphrates River (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000042; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Women; Rivers; Iraq; Houses; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; English Writing; Euphrates River
- Left: a dried river bed; Right: a group portrait of five servicemen., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000043; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Rivers; Men; Uniforms; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iraq; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers
- Group portraits of five servicemen posing with a dog in Habbaniyah, Iraq., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000044; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Al Habbaniyah (Habbaniya), Al-Anbar Province, Iraq; Photographic Prints; Men; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Dogs; Animals; Royal Air Force; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers
- Captioned: Magneto repair section.Left: a group portrait of five soldiers posing with a dog; Right: a group of two soldiers in Habbaniyah, Iraq., 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000045; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Dogs; Animals; Uniforms; English Writing; Royal Air Force; Al Habbaniyah (Habbaniya), Al-Anbar Province, Iraq; Military/Soldiers
- Views of Al Rashid Street in Baghdad, Iraq., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000046; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Streets/Roads; Cars/Trucks; Photographic Prints; Baghdad, Iraq; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Transportation; Shops; Architecture; Street Lamps
- Three portraits of servicemen., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000047; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  Men; Uniforms; Smoking; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Iraq; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Royal Air Force; Cigarettes; Military/Soldiers
- A poem entitled Demobilization Form (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks)., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_n000048; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
  English Writing; Iraq; Mumbai/Bombay, India; Poetry; Printed Materials; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers
- The back inside cover of RAF in Iraq and Sharjah VI., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_zbk01; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)
- The back cover of RAF in Iraq and Sharjah VI., Circa 1941 - 1942; nyuad_pa000001_zbk02; Sainty, C. J., Active circa 1941-1943; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_013_v.1)